<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-03-03T16:40:11+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">On the Self-Organized Criticality in Astrophysics</title><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/SelfOrganizedCriticality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Self-Organized Criticality in Astrophysics"/><published>2024-12-29T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-29T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/SelfOrganizedCriticality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/SelfOrganizedCriticality/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3> <p><a href="https://journals.aps.org/pra/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevA.38.364">Bak et al. 1988</a> discovered the self-organized criticality in many physical systems. At this state, the system is extremely sensitive to small fluctuations, which propagates quickly throughout large range and can cause the so called avalanche. They used a sand pile model to explain such picture. Increasing the slope of the sand pile somewhere will cause the pile to slide off once the slope is larger than a critical value. They have found that this picture can explain the commonly observed 1/f noise, and can also applied to explain the Kolmogorov turbulence model. With random fluctuations, the scale of avalanche, along with the avalanche lifetime, follows a power-law distribution. This feature is indicative of the SOC properties of the system.</p> <p>Recently <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.16052">Zhang et al. 2024</a> studied the waiting time distribution (WTD) of 147 TeV photons of the Brightes-Of-All-Time gamma-ray burst GRB 221009A, detected by LHAASO KM2A. They have found that the WTD is close to a power-law instead of exponential distribution of independent random events. Also, they have fitted the WT difference with Tsallis q-Gaussian distribution, which also yield a consistent q despite its deviation from the relation with power-law slope. They have concluded that light signals from GRB 221009A is not completely independent, and may exhibit some SOC properties.</p> <h3 id="self-organized-criticality">Self-Organized Criticality</h3> <p>Bak et al. built up a sand pile model and investigated its properties. They assumed that sand has a critical slope \(z_c\), beyond this value the sand will slide down to lower place. For the 1-D case, i.e. sand could only slide in two directions to their neighbor points, there is a minimally stable state, with the same slope \(z_c\) for every points. The minimally stable state is, according to Bak, an attractor of the system. For a system at this state, if another sand grain is dropped on the top of the pile, it will increase the \(z\) at that location where it is dropped, then slide to next point where it again increases the \(z\)… Finally it will fall down to the edge or the slide will stop where \(z&lt;z_c\).</p> <p>However, it’s not the case when extended to 2- or 3-D situations. Since in a multi-dimensional case, each spacial point is in correlation with multiple points, any fluctuation will propagate to their neighbors (i.e. each point has 4 neighbors in 2D case). Therefore, the minimally stable state in the 1D scenario is not stable any more, as any perturbation will trigger an avalanche with the scale of the minimally stable cluster.</p> <p>The 2-D and 3-D bounded numerical experiment yielded power-law distribution of both slide size and slide lifetime. This will explain the observed 1/f noise, where the power spectrum is \(S(f) \propto f^{-2+\alpha}\). Here f is the frequency of the noise, and \(\alpha\) is the power-law slope of the lifetime distribution.</p> <h3 id="waiting-time-distribution-and-astrophysical-application">Waiting Time Distribution and Astrophysical Application</h3> <p>In astrophysical events, such as gamma-ray bursts, photons are treated as originated from a point source, regardless of the spatial location of photon emission. Thus by statistics of the waiting time (the time interval between detection of two events) could be used to yield information of randomness of photon emission. If events are randomly generated, i.e. from a SOC system, the avalanche induced is fully independent of the initial perturbation. In such a case, photons all follow a Poisson distribution. For a continuously changing emission rate, the waiting time distribution is thus a superposition of separate exponential distribution, which results in many cases in a power-law WTD. While other mechanisms can also produce similar power-law properties as SOC process, they could be distinguished by the statistics of waiting time. SOC process are random and spacial independent, e.g. earthquakes. However, the aftershock occurs around each earthquake, with a Dirac-\(\delta\) like spacial distribution at each earthquakes. The influence of such spacial dependence will be reflected in WTD, i.e. for events with clusterization, the power-law slope of WTD will be \(p\sim 2\), while for gradually varying events, \(p\lesssim 3\).</p> <p>For flaring stars, the variability timescale are small, which is assumed due to flares and micro-flares. Given the low counts rate, waiting time statistics of single photons instead of each flare are studied. Another example is the black hole accretion disk, where variability timescales are at 10 ms. WTD of such peaks follow Poisson statistics, indicating the peaks originate from a SOC process. Indeed, theoretical model of reservoir agrees with the detected WTD. It is assumed that as soon as mass in the reservoir exceed a critical value, it collapses inward, inducing an avalanche and produces a peak in the light curve by Bremsstrahlung. After each big pulse, mass needs time to cumulate in the reservoir in order to produce next pulse. Though observed WTD deviates from the simple stationary Poisson process, it might not contradict to the SOC picture if modification from additional effects such as size limit, time variability and spacial inhomogeneity are considered.</p> <h3 id="waiting-time-distribution-of-grb-221009a-vhe-photons">Waiting Time Distribution of GRB 221009A VHE Photons</h3> <p>The distribution of \(dT_n = T_{n+1}-T_n\) could be fitted with a power-law function with threshold. Also, the difference of \(dT_n\), i.e. \(x_i = (dT_{i+n}-dT_i)/\sigma_i\) could be fitted with a Tsallis q-Gaussian function. For different n, the parameter of q-Gaussian function is constant, revealing some scale invariance. Yet, the WTD power-law slope \(\alpha\) and the q-Gaussian index \(q\) does not agree with the theoretical relation \(\alpha = 2/(q-1)\). As the power-law distribution is indicative of the self-organized criticality, this deviation might due to the lack of independence of photons, according to the authors.</p> <p>In a structured jet model, GRB 221009A is thought to have a Poynting-flux-dominated core and a matter-dominated wing. Photons from the core is produced by magnetic dominated processes, which corresponds to some SOC systems. Though the conclusion in this work is not very strong, it provides a new perspective of the holistic characteristics of the system as a supplement to conventional spectral and temporal analysis.</p> <p align="right">by Xingwei Gong</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="GRB"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, Zhang et al. 2024 studied the waiting time distribution of GRB221009A afterglow VHE photons. This post is to summarize their findings]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LHAASO - LLM for Astrophsics Seminar Note</title><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/LLMConferenceNote/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LHAASO - LLM for Astrophsics Seminar Note"/><published>2024-12-26T16:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-26T16:04:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/LLMConferenceNote</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/LLMConferenceNote/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-llm-the-tasks-of-lhaaso-that-asks-for-ai-solutions">Why LLM? The tasks of LHAASO that asks for AI solutions</h2> <h3 id="background-reduction">Background Reduction</h3> <ul> <li>The gamma-ray background of LHAASO mainly consists of mis-classified cosmic rays. At present, LHAASO Collaboration reduces the background events by setting a threshold. Traditional method needs to perform a multi-dimensional optimization problem for each event in a 5-dimensional parameter space. This is not only time-consuming but also demands lots of computation resource.</li> <li>For KM2A, distinguishing gamma from protons is easier - gamma-ray air shower events produce mostly electron-positron pairs, while the latter is muon-rich. However, it’s not easy to do this on WCDA, a result from the insensitivity for muons. More often, events are categorized by its morphology. Given that proton cascade produce more secondary particles moving in random direction, the cascade is more extended than gamma events. By measuring the dispersion of secondary particles from the core position, both proton and gamma events exhibit Gaussian-like distributions, with larger mean value for protons. Thus by setting a threshold and ignore all of the events with dispersion lareger than the threshold, high classification purity is achieved at the cost of lower selection efficiency. </li> <li>The goal of using AI tools is to reduce the cosmic ray background by a factor of 2-5. This might not be a great improvement for bright sources like crab, but for faint targets, i.e. flux equivalent to 0.01 crab, reducing background is of great importance in enhancing significance of detection.</li> </ul> <h3 id="particle-categorization">Particle Categorization</h3> <p></p> <ul> <li>There are 26 different categories of cosmic ray particles, from H to Fe. Theoretically, these events have different location of cascade maxima, thus could be classified according to observations of WFCTA. This is however almost impossible in practise due to low quality of WFCTA imaging and the influence of cascade location and observation angle.</li> </ul> <h3 id="noise-reduction">Noise Reduction</h3> <ul> <li>Noise is quite common for both ED, MD and WCD. Assuming that secondary particles from a single event arrive at a flat surface in the space of x,y and t, noise outside this surface could be reduced. However, this will certainly exclude some signals, and noise in the surface is not distinguishable.</li> </ul> <h3 id="event-reconstruction">Event Reconstruction</h3> <ul> <li>Event reconstruction is highly dependent on air shower simulations. Detector array can only do discrete sampling of signals. If AI tools can do some kind of “interpolation” but with prior knowledge from simulations, the reconstruction error will be smaller.</li> </ul> <h3 id="multiple-source-analysis">Multiple Source Analysis</h3> <ul> <li>Near the milky way, source is dense and overlap, posing challenge to source identification. AI tools could help in analysis of source, resolving the contribution from each source.</li> </ul> <h2 id="zhejiang-lab-llm-application-to-astronomy">Zhejiang Lab LLM Application to Astronomy</h2> <h3 id="科学模型">科学模型</h3> <p>困难：有监督的训练数据很少</p> <p>生物大分子的研究，机器学习和冷冻电镜精度相差不大–可以先通过ai计算可信性再进行精确分析</p> <h3 id="为什么要做科学模型">为什么要做科学模型</h3> <p>《A new golden age of discovery》</p> <ul> <li>帮助科学家获取知识</li> <li>生成、标注大型数据集</li> <li>模拟复杂实验并加速</li> <li>建模复杂系统</li> <li>大规模参数空间搜索</li> </ul> <p>GPT - 1e12 参数</p> <ul> <li>ChatGPT的组成： GPT + Chat</li> <li>GPT 无监督模型 <ul> <li>噪声数据经过编码也可以帮助训练</li> <li>GPT的任务是将数据编码</li> </ul> </li> <li>Chat为有监督学习，（指令跟随）</li> <li>基础模型与CPT,SFT… <ul> <li>基础模型GPT,021,LLaMa等，将数据压缩编码</li> <li>SFT， instruction model,指令模型</li> <li>或者GPT+CPT+SFT，CPT是领域模型（特化数据对基础模型进行微调），对特定领域进行优化</li> </ul> </li> <li>一般而言，基础模型的训练数据不包含最专业的数据 （语料库包含大量生物医药语料，不包含高能物理等），加入领域的语料进行基础模型的训练，形成领域模型。基础模型一般很宽泛</li> </ul> <h3 id="大模型为什么大">大模型为什么大</h3> <ul> <li>充分算力 – GPU</li> <li>大量数据,数据驱动–Token （B-T之间的数据规模）</li> <li> <p>基于模型 Transformer</p> </li> <li>科学基础模型+ 地学+天文（GeoGPT,AstroOne）能力迁移+ 科学工作空间</li> </ul> <h3 id="科学基础模型">科学基础模型</h3> <p>文理兼修，能成为未来科学家的辅助（大脑），然后开发工具（手脚）</p> <ol> <li>提出解决方法，将问题处理流程化</li> <li>AI科学家，看到问题，提出问题</li> </ol> <p>1+N模型（基准模型，多领域）-&gt;支撑领域专家模型（混合专家模型MOE）</p> <h3 id="科学基础模型-数据">科学基础模型-数据</h3> <ol> <li>数据规模： 通用语料1e4B,科学数据（文本）匮乏（2e5篇论文只有130B）</li> <li>数据种类： 跨学科，多模态，多尺度</li> <li>数据对齐： 数据模态能够转化</li> </ol> <h3 id="科学基础模型推理能力">科学基础模型–推理能力</h3> <p>多模态数据对齐增强 ，知识图谱 ，Q*算法 ，外部工具辅助验证（模拟器，代码解释器等）</p> <h4 id="geogpt-地学语言模型">GeoGPT-地学语言模型</h4> <p>辅助地学科学家进行数据统计分析，知识整理等辅助性研究，从论文中抽取数据信息</p> <p>300B领域语料，基于021科学基础模型，qwen等</p> <h4 id="天文大模型">天文大模型</h4> <p>天文大语言模型 + 恒星光谱模型等科学模型</p> <p>一个语言模型+ 图文解释模型 + 其余科学模型： 1+1+X</p> <p><strong>同样面临无法验证的问题</strong></p> <p>太阳耀斑活动预测（感觉可迁移至提升灵敏度）以及特征提取 （跨模态重构，太阳光学成像与磁场成像重构，郝奇组）</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Conference"/><category term="ML"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I attended a meeting of IHEP LHAASO Collaboration and Zhejiang Lab. This is the note taken from the meeting]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Non-thermal Particle from Maximum Entropy</title><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/MaximumEntropy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Non-thermal Particle from Maximum Entropy"/><published>2024-12-20T15:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T15:04:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/MaximumEntropy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/MaximumEntropy/"><![CDATA[<p>Recent works proposed a novel model to account for the power-law non-thermal particle accelerated in turbulence (<a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2022PhRvX..12c1011Z/abstract">Zhdankin 2022a</a>, <a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2022JPlPh..88c1703Z/abstract">2022b</a>).</p> <h3 id="casimir-invariants-and-casimir-momentum">Casimir Invariants and Casimir Momentum</h3> <p>The Vlasov equation gives the dynamical evolution of collisionless plasma,</p> \[\begin{equation} \partial _t f + v \cdot \nabla f = -F\cdot \frac{\partial f}{\partial p} \end{equation}\] <p>where LHS is the convective derivative, and RHS is the force, including the EM term and external term. \(f\) is the particle distribution function.</p> <p>For a rising function \(g(f)\) with good enough properties, \(\frac{1}{N}\int d^3x d^3p g(f)\) is conserved, as long as f is described by Vlasov equation. Thus a set of \(g(f)\) is called Casimir invariants. A special invariant is found with dimension of momentum: the so called Casimir momentum.</p> \[\begin{equation} p_{c,\chi}(f) = n_0^{1/3} \left(\frac{1}{N} \int d^3x d^3p f^\chi\right) ^{-\frac{1}{3(\chi-1)}}, \end{equation}\] <p>where \(\chi&gt;0\) is a free index. The Casimir momentum is equivalent with the Renyi entropy in its integral of phase space, and thus is a generalized entropy. Spacial inhomogeneity will result in decrease of the entropy, while energy injection will produce entropy.</p> <h3 id="power-law-particle">Power-Law Particle</h3> <p>With particle number conservation and energy conservation, and from the maximal entropy condition, it naturally leads to a power-law particle spectrum:</p> \[\begin{equation} f = C[E(p)/E_b+1]^{-\frac{1}{1-\chi_d}} ,\end{equation}\] <p>where \(E_b\) and \(C\) is the normalization factor from the Lagrange multipliers.</p> <p>In relativistic limit, there is</p> \[\begin{equation} f\xrightarrow{\text{UR}}C(p/p_b+1)^{-\alpha-2} ,\end{equation}\] <p>where \(\alpha = (2\chi_d-1)/(1-\chi_d)\) </p> <p>In non-relativistic limit, there is</p> \[\begin{equation} f\xrightarrow{\text{NR}}C(p^2/p_b^2+1)^{-\alpha-1/2} ,\end{equation}\] <p>where \(\alpha = (\chi_d+1)/2(1-\chi_d)\).</p> <p>For \(\chi=1\), \(f\) returns to the thermal distribution.</p> <p>Comparing the maximal \(p_{c,\chi_d}\) with the \(p_{c,\infty}\), the physical condition corresponding to certain \(\alpha\) is</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} \eta \left(\frac{\delta B}{B_0}\right)^2\frac{1}{\beta_c} = &amp; \left(\frac{\alpha+1}{\alpha-2}\right)^{\frac{\alpha+2}{3}}-e\\ \eta \left(\frac{\delta B}{B_0}\right)^2\frac{1}{\beta_c} = &amp; \left(\frac{\alpha-1/2}{\alpha-2}\right)^{\frac{2\alpha+1}{3}}-e \end{aligned}, \end{equation}\] <p>for relativistic and non-relativistic cases respectively. \(\alpha\) is the particle SED power-law slope, \(\left(\frac{\delta B}{B_0}\right)^2\) is the strength of turbulence, \(\eta\) and \(e\) are coefficients with \(E_{c,\chi_d} \sim eE_0 + \eta F_{\mathrm{free}}\).</p> <h3 id="summary">Summary</h3> <p>In these works, one of the Casimir invariants is considered, which has the same dimension with momentum. This invariant is related to the Gibbs entropy. From the argument that entropy is maximized in a system, this model naturally produces a power-law particle distribution. Because the Casimir momentum is physically meaningful, physical conditions could be roughly estimated for non-thermal particles with given power-law slope. These results indicate a \(\alpha \to 2\) after sufficiently long time in the strong turbulence regime with \(\left(\frac{\delta B}{B_0}\right)^2\frac{1}{\beta_c} \gg 1\).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="StochasticAcceleration"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reading note of a few papers, introducing the theoretical framework of maximum entropy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Generalized Fermi Acceleration Reading Note</title><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/Lemoine19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Generalized Fermi Acceleration Reading Note"/><published>2024-12-19T04:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T04:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/Lemoine19</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/Lemoine19/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="kinetic-equation">Kinetic Equation</h3> <p>Electro-magnetic field is boosted to the frame in which electric field vanishes. This frame is not necessarily coincident with the fluid comoving frame unless ideal MHD is assumed. So the author defined a comoving locally inertial frame \(\mathcal{\hat{R}}_u\) In the particle comoving frame, the kinetic equation is written as</p> \[\begin{equation} \frac{\mathrm{d} \hat{p}^{\hat{a}}}{\mathrm{d}\tau} = \frac{q}{m} \hat{F}^{\hat{a}} _{\hat{ b}}\hat{p}^{\hat{b}} - \hat{\Gamma}^{\hat{a}}_{\hat{b}\hat{c}}\frac{\hat{p}^{\hat{b}}\hat{p}^{\hat{c}}}{m} ,\end{equation}\] <p>where the first term leads to pitch angle diffusion by electromagnetic field tensor, without changing the particle energy. The second term is the local coordinate, which changes with time and accelerates particle. The quantities with hat represent those in local inertial frame of particle.</p> <h4 id="spin-connection">Spin Connection</h4> <p>The \(\hat{\Gamma}^{\hat{a}}_{\hat{b}\hat{c}}\) here is the connection of the tetrad, which is defined as \(\hat{\Gamma}^{\hat{a}}_{\hat{b}\hat{c}} =-e_{\hat{b}}^\beta e_{\hat{c}}^\gamma e^{\hat{a}}_{\beta;\gamma}\), and the \(e^{\hat{a}}_{\beta;\gamma}\) is covariant derivative of the tetrad. For a simple example, we now assume a flat space-time of both lab frame and LIF, so the tetrad coefficients are just the Lorentz transformation matrix, with \(u^x\) the only non-zero spatial component of 4-velocity , i.e.</p> \[\begin{equation} e_\alpha^{\hat{a}} = \Lambda_\alpha^{\hat{a}} = \begin{bmatrix} u^t&amp;-u^x&amp;0&amp;0&amp;\\ -u^x&amp;u^t&amp;0&amp;0\\ 0&amp;0&amp;1&amp;0\\ 0&amp;0&amp;0&amp;1 \end{bmatrix}\label{conn} \end{equation}\] <p>and the inverse transformation is obtained by substituting \(-u^x\) with \(u^x\).</p> <p>Then we can simply compute the coefficients, e.g. \(\hat{\Gamma}_{\hat{1}\,\hat{0}}^{\hat{0}} = -e_{\hat{1}}^\beta e_{\hat{0}}^\gamma e^{\hat{0}}_{\beta;\gamma}\) Substitute the above \eqref{conn} into this equation, we obtain (for \(\{(\beta, \gamma)\} \in \{(0,0),\,(1,0),\,(0,1),\,(1,1)\}\)) \(\hat{\Gamma}_{\hat{1}\,\hat{0}}^{\hat{0}} = -u^xu^tu^t_{,t} + (u^t)^2 u^x_{,t} - (u^x)^2 u^t_{,x} + u^xu^tu^x_{,x}\). Then we differentiate the normalization of 4-velocity u \((u^t)^2-(u^t)^2 = 1\), so \(u^t u^t_{,a} = u^x u^x_{,a}\) and then simplify the above equation, we get \(\hat{\Gamma}_{\hat{1}\,\hat{0}}^{\hat{0}} = u^x_{,t} + \beta u^x_{,x}\).</p> <p>This is the simplest example of computing the connection coefficient. Though the geometry of lab frame may be non-trivial, the calculation of the connection follows the same procedure.</p> <h3 id="energy-gain">Energy Gain</h3> \[\begin{equation} \Delta p^t(\Delta \tau) = [e^t_{\hat{a}}(\Delta \tau)- e^t_{\hat{a}}(0)]\hat{p}^{\hat{a}}(0) + e^t_{\hat{a}}(\Delta \tau)\int_0^{\Delta\tau} \mathrm{d}\tau_1 \frac{\mathrm d \hat{p}^{\hat{a}}}{\mathrm{d}\tau _1} \end{equation}\] <p>Here the first term describes Fermi acceleration, and second term is the particle kinetic evolution in its local frame. \hat{\beta} \(e^t_{\hat{a}}\) is the Vierbein of relativistic transformation, which is defined by \(g_{\mu\nu} = e^{\hat{\alpha}}_\mu e^{\hat{\beta}}_\nu \eta_{\hat{\alpha}\hat{\beta}}\).</p> <p>As an application of this framework, the conclusions of shock acceleration could be reproduced (in Section II).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="StochasticAcceleration"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reading note of Lemoine 2019 PhRvD, the theoretical framework of generatlized Fermi acceleration]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blandford-McKee 1976 Reading Note</title><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/BM76/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blandford-McKee 1976 Reading Note"/><published>2024-12-12T14:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-12T14:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/BM76</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/BM76/"><![CDATA[<p>This post is to take some reading notes of <a href="https://doi.org/10.1063/1.861619">Blandford-McKee 1976 </a> self-similar solution, and derive the main equations in detail.</p> <h2 id="relativistic-shock-jump-condition">Relativistic Shock Jump Condition</h2> <p>Define the dimensionless 4-velocity \(u = ds/cd\tau\), therefore spacial component of u is \(\gamma \beta\), and time component is \(1\).</p> <p>We further define the relative dimensionless velocity \(\beta_{ij}\), e.g. \(\beta_{1s}\) the relative velocity between shock and upstream unshocked plasma. From SR, we easily get the following relations</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} &amp;\beta_{1s} = \frac{\beta_{2s}+\beta_{21}}{1+\beta_{2s}\beta_{21}}\\ &amp;\beta_{2s} = \frac{\beta_{1s}-\beta_{21}}{1-\beta_{1s}\beta_{21}}\\ &amp;\beta_{21} = \frac{\beta_{1s}-\beta_{2s}}{1-\beta_{1s}\beta_{2s}}\\ &amp;\gamma_{1s} = \gamma_{2s}\gamma_{21}(1+\beta_{2s}\beta_{21})\\ &amp;\gamma_{2s} = \gamma_{1s}\gamma_{21}(1-\beta_{1s}\beta_{21})\\ &amp;\gamma_{21} = \gamma_{1s}\gamma_{2s}(1-\beta_{1s}\beta_{2s})\\ &amp;u_{1s} = \gamma_{2s}\gamma_{21}(\beta_{21}+\beta_{2s})\\ &amp;u_{2s} = \gamma_{1s}\gamma_{21}(\beta_{1s}-\beta_{21})\\ &amp;u_{21} = \gamma_{1s}\gamma_{2s}(\beta_{1s}-\beta_{2s}) \end{aligned} \end{equation}\] <p>This is useful to obtain jump conditions in upstream rest frame. The shock needs to satisfy mass, momentum and energy conservation. In shock frame, the conservation condition could be derived from \(\partial_x T^{1\nu} = 0\). Obviously we must first have the particle number conservation</p> \[\begin{equation} \langle nu\rangle = \langle n\gamma \beta \rangle = 0 \end{equation}\] <p>Then from \(\partial_x T^{00} = 0\) follows the energy conservation condition:</p> \[\begin{equation} \langle \gamma^2 h \beta\rangle = \langle \gamma h u\rangle = 0 .\end{equation}\] <p>From \(\partial_x T^{01} = 0\), we have the momentum conservation:</p> \[\begin{equation} \langle \gamma^2 \beta^2 h +p\rangle = \langle hu^2+p\rangle = 0 \end{equation}\] <p>here \(h\) is the enthalpy in unit volume in fluid rest frame. We need to note that the \(n, p, e , h\) are all quantities in the fluid rest frame. The relativistic transformation is contained in the dimensionless 4-speed.</p> <h2 id="rankine-hugoniot-condition-for-cold-upstream">Rankine-Hugoniot Condition for Cold upstream</h2> <p>Cold upstream means that \(e_1 = \rho_1 c^2, p_1= 0\). Thus from the equation of state \(p = (\hat{\gamma} - 1)(e - \rho c^2)\), there is \(\frac{p}{n} = (\hat{\gamma}-1)(\frac{e}{n}-mc^2)\). If the internal energy at upstream \(e_1-\rho c^2=0\), since the \(e/n\) is Lorentz invariant, we have</p> \[\begin{equation} \frac{e_2}{n_2} = \gamma_{21} m c^2 \end{equation}\] <p>Therefore,</p> <p>\(\frac{p_2}{n_2} = (\hat{\gamma}-1)(\gamma-1) mc^2\).</p> <p>From the energy conservation \(\gamma_{1s} h_1/n_1=\gamma_{2s} h_2/n_2\), we have \(\begin{equation} \frac{\gamma_{1s}}{\gamma_{2s}} = \hat{\gamma}(\gamma_{21} -1)+1 \end{equation}\)</p> <p>Keep this in mind and substitute it into</p> \[\gamma_{2s} = \gamma_{1s}\gamma_{21}(1-\beta_{1s}\beta_{21}),\] <p>eliminate \(\gamma_{2s}\) and after a bit complicated formulation we get</p> \[\begin{equation} \gamma_{1s}^2 = \frac{(\gamma_{21} + 1)[\hat{\gamma}(\gamma_{21}-1)+1]^2}{\hat{\gamma}(2-\hat{\gamma} )(\gamma_{21}-1)+2}. \end{equation}\] <p>From Lorentz factor, we can directly write the dimensionless 4-velocity \(u^2 = \gamma^2 \beta^2 = \gamma^2-1\)</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} u_{1s}^2 = &amp;\frac{(\gamma_{21} - 1)(\gamma_{21}\hat{\gamma}+1)^2}{(\gamma_{21}-1)+2}\\ u_{2s}^2 =&amp;\frac{(\gamma_{21} - 1)(\hat{\gamma}-1)^2}{(\gamma_{21}-1)+2} \end{aligned} \end{equation}\] <p>Therefore, from \(u_{2s} n_{2} = u_{1s}n_1\), the compression ratio is</p> \[\begin{equation} \frac{n_2}{n_1} = \frac{\hat{\gamma}\gamma_{21}+1}{\hat{\gamma}-1} \end{equation}\] <p>These are the Rankine-Hugoniot conditions of relativistic shock, see eq. (3-5) in BM76.</p> <h2 id="energy-momentum-tensor">Energy-Momentum Tensor</h2> <p>The energy-momentum tensor could be expressed in the following form</p> \[\begin{equation} T^{\mu\nu} = (e+p) u^\mu u^\nu + p \eta ^{\mu\nu}, \end{equation}\] <p>where \(e\) is the energy density (internal energy + rest mass), \(p\) is the pressure, \(u = \gamma( 1,\beta_x,\beta_y,\beta_z)\) the dimensionless 4-velocity, \(\eta = (-1,1,1,1)\) the Minkowski metric.</p> <p>Specifically, if a relativistic fluid is moving with \(\beta\) in \(x\) direction, the complete matrix form of EM Tensor is</p> \[\begin{equation} T^{\mu\nu} = \left(\begin{matrix} \gamma^2h-p &amp; \gamma^2\beta h &amp; 0&amp;0\\ \gamma^2\beta h &amp; \gamma^2 \beta^2 h +p &amp; 0 &amp; 0 \\ 0&amp;0&amp;p&amp;0\\ 0&amp;0&amp;0&amp;p \end{matrix}\right) \end{equation}\] <p>Eq. (11) and (12) are in the spherical coordinate with angular symmetry. Thus \(\eta = (-1,1,r^2,r^2\sin^2\theta)\) and \(u = \gamma(1,\beta,0,0)\). We can now calculate the derivative of the EM Tensor,</p> \[\begin{aligned} &amp;\partial_0T^{00} = \frac{\partial (e+p)\gamma^2}{\partial t} - \frac{\partial p}{\partial t}\\ &amp;\partial_0T^{0r} = \frac{\partial (e+p)\gamma^2 \beta}{\partial t}\\ &amp;\partial_r T^{r0} = \frac{1}{r^2 } \frac{\partial}{\partial r } \left[r^2 (e+p)\gamma^2\beta\right]\\ &amp;\partial_r T^{rr} = \frac{1}{r^2 } \frac{\partial}{\partial r } \left[r^2 (e+p)\gamma^2\beta^2\right] + \frac{1}{r^2 } \frac{\partial}{\partial r } \left(r^2p\right) \end{aligned}\] <p>From the energy and momentum conservation, i.e. \(\nabla _{\mu} T^{\mu\nu} = 0\). Sum up the corresponding derivatives, for \(\nu = 0\), we get</p> \[\begin{equation} \frac{\partial}{\partial t } \frac{e+p\beta^2}{1-\beta^2}+\frac{1}{r^2 } \frac{\partial}{\partial r }\frac{r^2(e+p)\beta}{1-\beta^2}=0, \end{equation}\] <p>same as eq. (11).</p> <p>For \(\nu=1\),</p> \[\begin{equation} \frac{\partial }{\partial t}\frac{(e+p)\beta}{1-\beta^2}+ \frac{1}{r^2 } \frac{\partial}{\partial r } \frac{r^2 (e+p)\beta^2}{1-\beta^2} + \frac{\partial p}{\partial r} + \frac{2p}{r}. \end{equation}\] <p>There seems to be an additional \({2p}/{r}\) compared to eq. (12) of BM76.</p> <p>With \(e = 3p\) the ultra-relativistic approximation for equation of state, and using \(\gamma = 1/\sqrt{1-\beta^2}\), we expand eq (11-12,14-15).</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} (4\gamma^2-1)\frac{\partial p}{\partial t} + 8\gamma p \frac{\partial \gamma}{\partial t } + 4\gamma^2\beta\frac{\partial p }{\partial r} + 4p(2\gamma\beta + \frac{1}{\gamma \beta})\frac{\partial \gamma }{\partial r }+\frac{8p\gamma^2 \beta}{r}= 0&amp;\hspace{2em}\text{(eq. 11)}\\ 4 \gamma^2 \beta \frac{\partial p }{\partial t } + 4p(2\gamma \beta + \frac{1}{\gamma \beta})\frac{\partial \gamma }{\partial t } + (4 \gamma^2 -3 )\frac{\partial p}{ \partial r } + 8p\gamma \frac{\partial \gamma }{\partial r} + \frac{8p(\gamma^2-1)}{r } = 0&amp;\hspace{2em}\text{(eq. 12)}\\ \\ (\gamma^2-1)\frac{\partial p}{\partial t} + 4 \gamma p \frac{\partial \gamma}{\partial t } + 4 \beta p\gamma \frac{\partial \gamma}{\partial r} + \beta \gamma^2 \frac{\partial p }{\partial r }= 0&amp;\hspace{2em}\text{(eq. 14)}\\ 3\gamma^2 \frac{\partial p}{\partial t} + 4 \gamma p \frac{\partial \gamma }{\partial t } + 3\beta \gamma^2\frac{\partial p}{\partial r } + (4\gamma \beta p +\frac{4p}{\gamma\beta})\frac{\partial \gamma}{\partial r} + \frac{8\gamma^2 p\beta}{r} = 0&amp;\hspace{2em}\text{(eq. 15)} \end{aligned} \end{equation}\] <p>No additional approximations are made in the expansion above. Eq. 14 could be derived by combining eq. 11-12 and eliminate the \(p/r\) term. Eq. 15 is obtained by adding eq. 14 with eq. 11.</p> <p>Therefore,</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} \frac{d}{dt}(p\gamma^4) = &amp;\gamma^2 \frac{\partial p }{\partial t}&amp;\hspace{2em}\text{(eq. 14)}\\ \frac{d}{dt}\ln(p^3\gamma^4) = &amp;-\frac{4}{r^2} \frac{\partial}{\partial r}(r^2 \beta)&amp;\hspace{2em}\text{(eq. 15)} \end{aligned} \end{equation}\] <p>From the particle conservation \(\frac{\partial n'}{\partial t} = -\frac{1}{r^2}\frac{\partial }{\partial r }(r^2 n' \beta),\) we could yield \(\frac{dn'}{dt} = -\frac{n'}{r^2}\frac{\partial r^2\beta}{\partial r} = \frac{n'}{4}\frac{d}{dt}\ln(p^3\gamma^4)\)</p> <p>Thus</p> \[\frac{4}{n'}\frac{dn'}{dt} = \frac{n'}{4}\frac{d}{dt}\ln(p^3\gamma^4)\] <p>which turns into \(\begin{equation} \frac{d}{dt}\left(\frac{p^3\gamma^4}{n'^4}\right) = \frac{d}{dt}\left(\frac{p}{n^{4/3}} \right) = 0 \end{equation}\)</p> <h3 id="self-similar-solution-of-adiabatic-blast-wave">Self-Similar Solution of Adiabatic Blast Wave</h3> <p>The energy between R0 and R1 is \(E = \int_{R_0}^{R_1} 16 \pi p\gamma^2 r^2 dr\). In the coefficient,\(4\pi r^2\) is due to spherical coordinate, \(4\gamma^2p\) is the shocked energy density. Assuming an adiabatic expanding blast wave, the total energy is conserved \(E \propto R^3\Gamma^2\).</p> <p>Further assume \(\Gamma \propto t^{-m}\) with \(m &gt; -1\), first expand \(\beta\) with \(\Gamma\) to \(O(\Gamma^{-2})\)</p> \[R = \int \beta dt = t\left[1-\frac{1}{2(m+1)\Gamma^2}\right].\] <p>BM76 chose the self similar variable as</p> \[\begin{equation} \chi = [1+2(m+1) \Gamma^2]\left(1-\frac{r}{t}\right) \end{equation}\] <p>The post-shock fluid could write as</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} p =&amp; \frac{2}{3}h_1\Gamma^2 f(\chi)\\ \gamma_{21}^2 =&amp; \frac{1}{2}\Gamma g(\chi)\\ n' =&amp; 2n_1\Gamma^2 h(\chi) \end{aligned}, \end{equation}\] <p>where \(\Gamma = \gamma_{1s}\) is the shock Lorentz factor and \(\Gamma^2 = 2 \gamma_{21}^2\) in the ultra-relativistic limit. \(n'\) is seen from the upstream rest frame and \(n'= \gamma n_2\).</p> <p>Then we can substitute the old variables \(r,t\) with new variables \(\Gamma^2, \chi\). Be careful here that \(\Gamma^2 \propto t^{-m}\) and is independent upon \(r\). Then we have the elements of Jacobi Matrix,</p> \[\begin{aligned} t\frac{\partial \Gamma^2}{\partial t} =&amp; -m\Gamma^2\\ t\frac{\partial \Gamma^2 }{\partial r} = &amp;0\\ t\frac{\partial\chi}{\partial t} =&amp; (m+1)(2\Gamma^2-\chi)+1\\ t\frac{\partial\chi}{\partial r} =&amp; -[1+2(m+1)\Gamma^2] \end{aligned}\] <p>Specially, we have substituted \(\Gamma^2 =A t^{-m}\) to compute \(t\frac{\partial\chi}{\partial t}\). The old derivatives are now</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} &amp;\frac{\partial}{\partial\ln t} = -m\frac{\partial}{\partial \ln \Gamma^2}+ [(m+1)(2\Gamma^2-\chi)+1]\frac{\partial }{\partial\chi}\\ &amp;t\frac{\partial}{\partial r} = -[1+2(m+1)\Gamma^2]\frac{\partial }{\partial\chi}\\ &amp;\frac{d}{d\ln t} = -m\frac{\partial}{\partial \ln \Gamma^2}+ (m+1)\left(\frac{2}{g}-\chi\right)\frac{\partial }{\partial\chi} \end{aligned} \end{equation}\] <p>The third equation is from convective derivative \(d/dt = \partial_t + \beta_{21}\partial_r\). There is the function \(g\) because of the \(\beta_{21}\).</p> <p>Now we have the new derivatives. Just substitute them into (14-16), and only keep the terms with highest order of \(\Gamma^2\). Solve the linear equations and we get the self similar solution of adiabatic blast wave</p> \[\begin{equation} \begin{aligned} \frac{1}{g}\frac{d \ln f}{d\chi} =&amp; \frac{8(m-1)-(m-4)g\chi}{(m+1)(4-8g\chi+g^2\chi^2)}\\ \frac{1}{g}\frac{d \ln g}{d\chi} =&amp; \frac{(7m-4)-(m+2)g\chi}{(m+1)(4-8g\chi+g^2\chi^2)}\\ \frac{1}{g}\frac{d \ln h}{d\chi} =&amp; \frac{2(9m-8)-2(5m-6)g\chi + (m-2) g^2\chi^2}{(m+1)(4-8g\chi+g^2\chi^2)(2-g\chi)} \end{aligned} \end{equation}\] <p>There is no \(h\) in eq (14,15), so we could first align these two equations and solve derivative of \(f,g\).</p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="GRB"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A derivation of Blandford-McKee 1976 self similar solution for relativistic blast wave]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Report of PDS 456 Soft X-ray Observation</title><link href="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/AGNReport2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Report of PDS 456 Soft X-ray Observation"/><published>2024-12-05T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-05T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/AGNReport2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xwgong01.github.io/blog/2024/AGNReport2/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="main-idea">Main Idea</h2> <p>This paper (<a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020ApJ...895...37R/abstract">Reeves et al. 2020</a>) discussed new XMM-Newton observations in 2018 and 2019 of the luminous quasar PDS 456. The new observation shows significant soft X-ray absorption features along with Fe K absorption lines that already observed in previous works. The lines in the new observation could be well explained by absorption from ultra-fast outflow. The separate spectral fitting of two components, soft X-ray absorber and iron K absorber, yield same outflow velocity of \(\sim -0.25c\), consistent with previous studies of this source. The soft X-ray component shows strong variability while the iron K absorber is relative stable within the \(\sim 20\) day period of the two 2019 observations, indicating the two absorption features originate from diferent distances. The author gave theoretical interpretations of the observed features. This work is observational paper which could be rated as good. The conclusion of ultra fast outflow is strong, and calls for further investigation of this source with more advanced instruments like XRISM and ATHENA.</p> <h2 id="motivation">Motivation</h2> <p>PDS 456 is a luminous quasar with redshift \(z = 0.184\). Previous observations reveals the existence of iron K-shell absorption line profile with outflow velocity of \(\sim 0.25c\). It has been claimed that high-velocity iron K winds might be common in nearby AGNs due to numerous observations (e.g. APM 08279+5255, PG 1211+143). However, the detection of blue-shifted absorption lines in soft X-ray band is relatively rare. For the source PDS 456, soft X-ray outflow with lower ionization has been confirmed with the archival XMM-Newton observations. Soft X-ray fast winds has been reported in a few other sources, such as IRAS 13224-3809 and 1H 0707-495. There were also examples of co-existing soft X-ray and Fe K winds with consistent velocity, e.g. PG 1211+143 with \(v \sim -0.06c\) and IRAS 13224-3809 with \(v \sim 0.24c\). Despite the increasing observations, the correlation between iron K wind and soft X-ray wind was still poorly understood. This paper is motivated by three XMM-Newton observations, one in 2018 and two in 2019. The latter two observations were carried out with an interval \(\sim 20\) days. This provides a chance to examine the variability timescale of the outflow wind, providing constraints on the location, size and density. Furthermore, these new observations have resolved both the soft X-ray component and the iron K absorber, enabling detailed investigation of the exact relation between these two components.</p> <h2 id="data-and-methods">Data and Methods</h2> <p>The 2018 XMM-Newton observation was made on Sep.9, with 86 ks exposure, along with HST and NuSTAR observations. Observation 2019a was on Sep. 2, with 83 ks exposure, simultaneous with HST observation. 2019b was made on Sep 24., about 20 days after 2019a. This observation has 94 ks exposure and conducted simultaneously with NuSTAR. The 2018 observation is in the bright state, with energy flux \(F= 9.4\times 10^{-12}\) ergs cm, \(^{-2}s^{-1}\) at 2-10 keV. The soft X-ray spectrum of 2018 observation is featureless, while the hard X-ray spectrum extends to \(&gt; 50\)keV according to NuSTAR observation. Being about 5 times fainter than 2018 observation, both 2019 observations demonstrate Fe K absorption profile at 7-10 keV and soft X-ray absorption features, while 2019b is more significant. Interestingly, Swift monitoring shows that 2019a is almost at the state with minimum flux.</p> <p>The author mainly fitted the 2019b spectrum to investigate the properties of soft X-ray absorber. They first used gaussian-like profile to locate the three most significant absorption lines, then fitted it with blue-shifted photoionization model (XSTAR) with solar abundance. In addition to the fast outflow, they also tried fitting with models of low velocity shift, which was badly fitted and thus ruled out the latter assumption. In the broad-band fitting, the author also used XSTAR to identify the iron K absorption features – the 9 keV trough and the 10.2 keV trough. The former one is probably due too Fe XXVI Ly\(\alpha\) absorption line, with velocity shift consistent with the soft X-ray component; the latter requires a second faster wind component, with outflow velocity \(v \sim 0.36c\).</p> <h2 id="results-and-conclusion">Results and Conclusion</h2> <h3 id="soft-x-ray-absorber-spectral-fitting">Soft X-ray Absorber Spectral Fitting</h3> <p>At soft X-ray band, the fit with a power-law model with galactic absorption is poor, and there are absorption profiles in addition to the continuum. With three Gaussian profile, the fit was significantly improved. With the a priori knowledge that outflow velocity might be \(-0.25-0.3c\), the Gaussian absorption lines could be identified as OIII Ly\(\alpha\) (18.97 \(\AA\) ), Ne IX He\(\alpha\) (13.45 \(\AA\) ) and Ne X Ly\(\alpha\) (12.13 \(\AA\) ). All the three lines give a common velocity shift of \(v/c = -0.257\), in agreement with the previous studies. The fitting using photoionization model XSTAR further improves the fitting, with the expense of 3 extra free parameters. The fitting yield a ionization parameter \(\log\xi = 3.4\), column density \(N_H = 2.3\times 10^21\)cm\(^{-3}\), and a covering factor \(f_{\mathrm{cov}} = 0.92^{+0.08}_{-0.32}\). In order to confirm the outflow explanation, the author further fitted the soft X-ray spectrum with absorber of zero or small velocity shift. The EW upperlimit of lines, constrained by the non-detection of the accompanying lines, is significantly weaker than observation, thus the zero-blueshifit scenario could be ruled out.</p> <h3 id="fe-k-line-fitting">Fe K Line Fitting</h3> <p>The Fe K absorption line at 9 keV restframe could be identified with Fe XXVI Ly\(\alpha\), with velocity shift \(-0.25\pm 0.02c\), in perfect agreement with the soft X-ray absorber. The absorption trough at \(\sim 10.2\) keV cannot be explained by the same outflow, thus might calling for an additional absorption component with \(v= 0.36c\). Compared with soft X-ray wind, the Fe K absorber exhibit higher ionization parameter \(\log \xi = 5.0\), almost two orders of manitude larger than the soft X-ray wind. Its column density is also larger (\(N_H = 7\times 10^{23}\) cm\(^{-3}\)).</p> <h3 id="interpretation">Interpretation</h3> <p>The 2018 observation has a 2-10 keV flux 4 times stronger than 2019b. By fitting the 2018a observation with same photoionization model, ionization parameter \(\log \xi\) is 4 times stronger than 2019b, which corresponds to the flux variability. Meanwhile, the 2019a observation has lower ionization factor due to the low flux, and the best-fit column density is higher. By another fit with neutral partial covering absorber, the zero-blueshift scenario was ruled out.</p> <p>In this work, the author gave self-consistent estimations of the location and size of the soft X-ray absorber with observations 2019a and 2019b. Both observations result in \(\sim\) parsec distance from central BH estimated by the ionization luminosity and covering fraction. Interestingly, the assumption of 20-day variation timescale gave an estimate of absorber size \(\Delta R \sim 10^{15}-10^{16}\)cm, also agrees with the covering fraction. The soft X-ray absorber is believed to locate outside the high-ionization Fe K absorber, and possibly originate from the ultra-fast outflow. The mass outflow rate for a uniform soft X-ray wind exceeds the upper limit set by accretion rate, a strong implication of its clumpy nature, explaining the fast variability of column density and ionization parameter.</p> <h2 id="scientific-significance">Scientific Significance</h2> <p>This work contributes to the understanding of the correlation between absorbers in soft X-ray band and iron K band. With spectral fitting, the author built a clear physical picture of relative location of the two components, and gave interpretation of the observed features during three different times.</p> <p>This work not only enhances the understanding of the source PDS 456, but also have profound impact on larger topics. The discovery of the clumpy absorber provides observational evidence for the hypothesis that X-ray wind originate from the post-shock interstellar medium interacting with the ultra-fast outflow. The estimated outflow rate and filling fraction also hints on the possible role in energy feedback to the galaxy that the soft X-ray wind might play.</p> <h2 id="key-factor-leading-to-conclusion">Key Factor Leading to Conclusion</h2> <p>The observations in different state of PDS 456 made it possible to estimate the properties and locations of the absorption components. The authors have published several papers discussing about PDS 456. Along with the three observations mainly introduced in this paper, previous multi-wavelength observations of this source, and other objects exhibiting similar absorption features are also crucial in getting the conclusion.</p> <h2 id="possibilities-of-improvement">Possibilities of Improvement</h2> <p>The size \(\Delta R\) is estimated based on the covering fraction \(f_{\mathrm{cov}} &gt; 0.6\) for 2019b, that the soft X-ray wind has comparable size with corona. However, I doubt whether this transverse scale could be directly applied in estimation of the number density along the line of sight. If the outflow is intermittent, line of sight depth may vary and dependent on the morphology of the wind. Though a spherical approximation suffice for a rough estimate, it could be improved regarding the light curve monitored by Swift.</p> <p>Besides, PDS 456 is in the PV source list of XRISM. With unprecedented spectral resolution and sensitivity, there is no doubt that the new observation will provide evidences supporting or against the conclusions in this work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading"/><category term="AGN"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This reading report is part of the AGN coursework. In this post, Reeves+20 is introduced.]]></summary></entry></feed>